## **Ben Cook**

benthomascook28@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/ben-cook28/ | https://bencook28.github.io | https://github.com/BenCook28 | +1 (317) 750-1508

# **Junior Front End Developer**

Seeks to create as much value as possible. Creative, committed to continual learning, and known for taking on responsibilities as needed. Loves to bring new ideas into reality. To do so, became a front-end developer. Also has experience with backend. Developed strong written and spoken communication skills, polished presentation skills, and familiarity with Agile. Enjoys learning and using foreign languages, traveling, exercising, value investing, and learning and applying new technical skills.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript

CSS3

Sass

Github

AngularJS

MEAN Stack

SQL

jQuery

• HTML5

MERN Stack

Bootstrap

Git

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Assistant Financial Officer, The Fountain Trust Company, Covington, IN USA

June 2014 to June 2017

Made financial reports for management team, regulators, and auditors. Modeled budget assumptions. Forecasted results in varied scenarios and back-tested for accuracy. Hosted a student for a 2 day job shadow. Crafted PowerPoint slides and gave quarterly presentations. Reconciled balances and corrected discrepancies. Taught myself additional features in the core software and used this knowledge to create ad hoc reports.

- Collaborated in decisions affecting \$100 million bond portfolio in a team of 3, vetted bonds, percentile rose from around 50<sup>th</sup> to between 60<sup>th</sup> and 70<sup>th</sup>
- Mined data about teller transactions to schedule shifts more efficiently, saved \$254,000 per year and reduced Full-Time Equivalent Employees by 14%
- Conducted due diligence about bank acquisition which added \$72 million in assets and 3 branches while improving the bank's regulatory ratios, contributed to regulatory application

Caller, Admissions Office, Wabash College, Crawfordsville, IN USA

Fall 2010 - Spring 2014

- Recruited 18 year old males to an all-male liberal arts college in a small town
- Made 1,150 calls, connected with 300 students

Accounting Teacher, (A Teaching Center), Xi'an, Shaanxi Province, China

Feb. 2013 to June 2013

- Prepared & taught 3-hour-long accounting classes to 3 Chinese university students during my study abroad
- Covered a 2-week trip along the Silk Road, long weekend in Chengdu, China, and life for 5 months in China

Sales Intern, Leonard McDowell, Indianapolis, IN USA

**Summers 2012 and 2013** 

- Identified a lead that resulted in a \$10,000 document management software sale
- Arranged 16 software sales appointments and qualified leads at 3 trade shows

Business Immersion Program, Wabash College, Crawfordsville, IN USA

Summer 2011

- Explored 36 business school cases, mostly from Harvard Business School
- Divided responsibilities amongst a team of three to create and present a business plan

### **EDUCATION**

 Eleven Fifty Academy, Fishers, IN USA JavaScript Accelerated Learning Program August 2017

Wabash College, Crawfordsville, IN USA
BA History, Asian Studies minor, Magna Cum Laude

May 2017